Komal Amrutkar

komalamrutkar@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/komal-amrutkar-b22a0a74/

Summary

Recent Graduate with 3.97 GPA and internship experience in web development

Technical Skills

Proficient: JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, NextJS, Typescript, Redux, Recoil, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap,

Tailwind, Axios, Express, Elasticsearch, Postgres, Jest, Git, JIRA

Familiar: Webpack, Babel, AWS, AWS-CloudeFront, Docker, RDBMS, GraphQL, core Java,

Education

MS in Web Development Aug 2020 – Aug 2022

Wilmington University, Delaware

BE in Information Technology

Aug 2011 – May 2015 Pune University, India

Professional Experience

Populus Media Inc, Princeton, NJ

Mar 2022 – Aug 2022

UI Developer/React Developer

Populus media assists companies in reaching the most highly targeted healthcare audience imaginable. That involves using virtual care visits and first-party data to reach out to your base. They employ the patient visit structure to deliver appropriate content and marketing messages.

- Built the application using ReactJS, NextJS, Typescript and Tailwind
- Implemented custom reusable component for Pagination.
- Implemented Search functionality based on pagination results
- Used Recoil library for app wide state management
- Designed and developed REST APIs for keyword CRUD operations
- Worked on Elasticsearch DB schema design and developed interactions using Elasticsearch Javascript SDK

BMC Software, Pune India

Sept 2016 - Sept 2019

Associate Web Developer

BMC Remedy is an ITSM suite that keeps track of tickets. BMC Service Request Management (module of ITSM) allows IT and other business departments to easily define available services, publish them in a service catalog, and automate their fulfillment for the user community

- Worked on enhancement of workorder management module
- Implemented authentication using in-house SSO react library
- Used ReactJS and React-Redux for building customizable components
- Worked with back-end developers to build RESTful API.
- Utilized the new features of ES6 like arrow functions, literals, promises, closures etc. in React components

Academic Projects (Wilmington University)

Weather Application

 Developed full stack application using nodeJS and used "mapbox.com" and "weatherstack.com" APIs

Task Tracker Application

- Developed full stack application using ReactJS and implemented REST APIs
- Utilized built-in React hooks and functions to fetch, parse and store JSON response data